Wendy Teuchtler

Commented [1]: This is coming along nicely and can be submitted as your V3 once you either add a project or remove the placeholder:)

856.304.5039 | wteuchtler@yahoo.com | linkedin.com/in/wendy-teuchtler | https://github.com/wteuchtler

About Me

Through my background as a molecular science researcher, I enjoy the process of data coming together to form new insights on complicated problems. This led me to transition to data analytics. Throughout my career, I have gathered and organized information to transform it into actionable reports and I look forward to growing my skills in data analytics.

Data Skills

SQL

Power BI

Tableau

Excel

Agile Methodology

Data Experience

Data Analytics Apprentice, Nashville Software School

Expected grad date Jan 2023

Full-time bootcamp focusing on data analytics fundamentals and problems solving. Hands-on training in Python, SQL, Excel, Tableau, and Power BI with a focus on data storytelling, building reports, and creating dashboards. Used real-world datasets and included projects where findings were presented to stakeholders from the community. Instruction and teamwork done remotely through Zoom.

- Source code version control with Git/GitHub
- Retrieved and analyzed data using PostgresSQL queries, subqueries, and CTEs
- Analyzed data using Microsoft Excel, including using pivot tables and lookups, and used PowerPivot to connect to external data sources
- Built and deployed dashboards using Tableau and PowerBl

Projects

Project name- Project description. Hyperlink

Commented [2]: If you don't have projects to add for V3, remove this placeholder because we will send V3 to the employer you meet with for mock interviews.

Professional Experience

Research Technician II

Baylor College of Medicine/Texas Children's Hospital

Aug 2021- May 2022

Investigated molecular pathways related to hematologic diseases and management of day-to-day lab operations:

- Time sensitive DNA and RNA extractions for patient blood samples
- · Maintenance of biobank records for ICON ITP study

- Lab assays including qPCR, ELISA, culture of human primary cells, whole blood processing, flow cytometry
- Implemented new assay protocols
- Managed inventory of all chemical reagents and lab instruments
- Maintained quality standards and aseptic environment necessary for BSL II laboratory

Research Assistant

University of West Florida, University of Washington, Duke University

May 2017- Dec 2020

- Investigated impact of azaborine compounds on mitochondrial membrane potential in HeLa cells
- Studied effects of HAX-1 knockout on neutrophil NETs
- Identification of furrow-associated proteins in Chlamydomonas
- Studied Arp 2/3 complex using larval zebrafish model organisms
- Investigated the relationship between variant genes associated with ALS using *D. melanogaster* as a model system.
- Analyzed microfauna, microflora and chemical changes to Florida beaches and bayous
- Tested the most effective way to recrystallize the trifluoromethylator pharmaceutical reagent using a solvent, non-solvent system.

35N Signals Intelligence Analyst and Soldier

Jul 2009- Nov2013

United States Army, National Security Agency, Fort Meade MD

- Top Secret SCI clearance (out of scope)
- Reported troop activity on over 350 strategic targets leading to hundreds of status-of-forces reports, including aiding the National Geospatial Intelligence Agency in the discovery of adversary training areas, which were subsequently entered into a centralized database for multi-agency use.
- Authored thousands of high-visibility reports, working with various intelligence agencies. Gathered and interpreted signals intelligence data and digital network data for further dissemination.
- Participated in military software training program, and developed training procedures that decreased training time by 50%
- Trained new team members on day-to-day signals operations

Education

Data Analytics Bootcamp Certification Nashville Software School	2023	
B.S. in Biomedical Sciences (4.0 GPA, summa cum laude) University of West Florida, Pensacola FL	2016-2020	
35N Signals Intelligence Training Army Signals Intelligence Training SCIF, San Angelo, TX	2011	
Awards and Achievements		

NIH Maximizing Access to Research Careers (MARC) U-STAR Award

2018-2020

UWF Summer of Undergraduate Research Program (SURP) Award	2017
National Security Agency/ Central Security Service Office of Russia	2013
U.S. Army Joint Service Achievement Medal	2013
Publications "Structures of the Oxidized States of Some Common Biochemical Reducing Agents," A. T. Royappa, A. L. Rheingold, W. C. Teuchtler, N. L. Auld; J. Mol. Struct. (2019) DOI: 10.1016/J.MOLSTRUC. 2019.127268	Fall 2019
"Arnold L. Rheingold, A. Timothy Royappa, Niccole L. Auld, Wendy C. Teuchtler, CSD Communication, 2017 (refcode XAPGUT)."	Spring 2017